<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advice on Treppenwitze</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/categories/advice/</link><description>Recent content in Advice on Treppenwitze</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator><language>en</language><copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 15:53:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/categories/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mindulness - What, Why and Why not</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/mindulness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 15:53:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/mindulness/</guid><description>What A state where there is heightened awareness of one’s present experience without judgment. You slow down, observe and experience your thoughts, feelings, bodily sensations, and surrounding environment without complaints, criticism, excitement or distress. Why Shapiro etal study proves the following benefits reduce self-reported state and trait anxiety reduce reports of overall psychological distress including depression. increase scores on overall empathy levels increase scores on a measure of spiritual experiences assessed at termination of intervention.</description></item><item><title>Checklists - What, How and Why</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/checklists/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 13:54:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/checklists/</guid><description>What Breaking abstract ideas down into a series of small actionable chunks
Why Convert theoretical knowledge from reading to practice (tacit knowledge to explicit knowledge). Eg: Reading a book, imitating a good some workflow Make connections between fragmented knowledge. The act of creating a checklist forces the mind to think of all the parts involved in completing a task. Minimizes uncertainty and anxiety.. Almost anything can be reduced to a series of steps — an algorithm.</description></item><item><title>Time Blocking - What, Why and How</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/time-blocking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/time-blocking/</guid><description>What Divide day into blocks of time dedicated to separate tasks
Why Open ended todo lists is less effective as you do easy tasks first, leaving frogs uneaten Helps to avoid perfectionism Helps to club shallow tasks and do more deep work How Prioritise task list using a weekly review and create and rough outline of time blocks At the end of day, review tasks that remain unfinished and adjust time blocks of the rest of the week Batch shallow tasks Have leisure blocks.</description></item><item><title>Bad ideologies - Criteria</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/spotting-bad-ideology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/spotting-bad-ideology/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Doubt each old thing you know. Require current evidence. Make it prove itself to be true today. Otherwise, let it go.&amp;rdquo; - really cannot remember who said it.
What is an ideology An ideology is a coherent set of ideas that should help you make sense of the world.
Set of normative beliefs and values that a person or other entity hold.
Normative : Standard for evaluating or making judgments about behavior or outcomes.</description></item></channel></rss>