<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advice on Treppenwitze</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/categories/advice/</link><description>Recent content in Advice on Treppenwitze</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 15:53:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/categories/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mindulness - What, Why and Why not</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/mindulness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 15:53:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/mindulness/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what">What&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A state where there is heightened awareness of one’s present experience without judgment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You slow down, observe and experience your thoughts, feelings, bodily sensations, and surrounding environment without complaints, criticism, excitement or distress.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="why">Why&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1018700829825" target="_blank">Shapiro etal study&lt;/a> proves the following benefits
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>reduce self-reported state and trait anxiety&lt;/li>
&lt;li>reduce reports of overall psychological distress including depression.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>increase scores on overall empathy levels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>increase scores on a measure of spiritual experiences assessed at termination of intervention.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preliminary functional neuro-imaging studies provides proof of improving emotional regulation by &lt;strong>enhancing cortical regulation of limbic circuits and attentional control&lt;/strong> -&lt;a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/070674371205700202" target="_blank">Walter Sipe etal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improve attention-related behavioral responses by enhancing functioning of specific sub-components of attention - &lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/6167711_Mindfulness_training_modifies_subsystems_of_attention" target="_blank">Jha etal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Higher mindfulness scores were associated with greater satisfaction with the environment and this association showed persistence - &lt;a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.3402/meo.v21.30664" target="_blank">Xi Xu etal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Methodologically rigorous RCTs have demonstrated that mindfulness interventions improve outcomes in multiple domains (e.g., chronic pain, depression relapse, addiction). &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27687118/" target="_blank">David Creswell 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mindfulness training improved both GRE reading-comprehension scores and working memory capacity while simultaneously reducing the occurrence of distracting thoughts during completion of the GRE and the measure of working memory. Improvements in performance following mindfulness training were mediated by reduced mind wandering among participants who were prone to distraction at pretesting. - &lt;a href="https://scottbarrykaufman.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mrazek-et-al.-2013-Mindfulness-Improves-WMC-GRE-Focus.pdf" target="_blank">Michael D. Mrazek etal, 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The default mode of humans appears to be that of mind-wandering, which correlates with unhappiness, and with activation in a network of brain areas associated with self-referential processing. We investigated brain activity in experienced meditators and matched meditation-naive controls as they performed several different meditations (Concentration, Loving-Kindness, Choiceless Awareness). We found that the &lt;strong>main nodes of the default-mode network (medial prefrontal and posterior cingulate cortices) were relatively deactivated in experienced meditators&lt;/strong> across all meditation types. Furthermore, functional connectivity analysis revealed &lt;strong>stronger coupling in experienced meditators between the posterior cingulate, dorsal anterior cingulate, and dorsolateral prefrontal cortices (regions previously implicated in self-monitoring and cognitive control), both at baseline and during meditation.&lt;/strong> Our findings demonstrate differences in the default-mode network that are consistent with decreased mind-wandering. - &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3250176/" target="_blank">Judson A. Brewer etal, 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="why-not">Why not&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ref: &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2019/jun/14/the-mindfulness-conspiracy-capitalist-spirituality" target="_blank">The Mindulness conspiracy by Ronald Purser&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Checklists - What, How and Why</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/checklists/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 13:54:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/checklists/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what">What&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Breaking abstract ideas down into a series of small actionable chunks&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why">Why&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Convert theoretical knowledge from reading to practice (tacit knowledge to explicit knowledge). Eg: Reading a book, imitating a good some workflow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make connections between fragmented knowledge. The act of creating a checklist forces the mind to think of all the parts involved in completing a task.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minimizes uncertainty and anxiety..
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Almost anything can be reduced to a series of steps — an algorithm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a team setting checklists democratize power. They are meant to be shared with your team because this allows you to put all brains on the problem.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how">How&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Ask: What do you want to accomplish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collate: Collect a list of reputable and proven sources.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Analyse the data with respect to the following:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Is it useful for my aim?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can I apply this?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What other data do I need?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How does this link with other data I have?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Connect: Form an outline from the data you collected&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Draft the checklist: Invert- start with endpoint in mind. It should involve the how as detailed as needed, data and definitions, examples&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Test and revise&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;hr>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Every checklist must have clear &amp;lsquo;pause points&amp;rsquo;. Pause points are moments during a task where one should stop and run through the lists before moving forward.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the task requires a long check list, then the task needs to be broken down into subtasks(with more narrow focus) before imposing checklists on it.&lt;br>
Eventually you won&amp;rsquo;t need the checklist&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Time Blocking - What, Why and How</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/time-blocking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/time-blocking/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what">What&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Divide day into blocks of time dedicated to separate tasks&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why">Why&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open ended todo lists is less effective as you do easy tasks first, leaving frogs uneaten&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Helps to avoid perfectionism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Helps to club shallow tasks and do more deep work&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how">How&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Prioritise task list using a weekly review and create and rough outline of time blocks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At the end of day, review tasks that remain unfinished and adjust time blocks of the rest of the week&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Batch shallow tasks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have leisure blocks. However try and be spontaneous in what leisure activity you choose to do there&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have pause blocks/overflow blocks - or even overflow days&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be flexible. If something does not go according to plan readjust blocks depending on priority. Time blocks are suggestions, not prisons.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be liberal with time allotment to tasks until you get a realistic grip on the time required for the same.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optional: You can combine time-boxing to test Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s law.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Bad ideologies - Criteria</title><link>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/spotting-bad-ideology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnishak.github.io/blog/post/spotting-bad-ideology/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Doubt each old thing you know. Require current evidence. Make it prove itself to be true today. Otherwise, let it go.&amp;rdquo; - really cannot remember who said it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-is-an-ideology">What is an ideology&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>An ideology is a coherent set of ideas that should help you make sense of the world.&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Set of normative beliefs and values that a person or other entity hold.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Normative&lt;/strong> : Standard for evaluating or making judgments about behavior or outcomes. Designating some actions or outcomes as good or desirable or permissible and others as bad or undesirable or impermissible.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>